[Music]
foreign
Professor Dave and Chegg here we know
that spectroscopy is the study of the
interaction of light and matter we can
use this interaction to gather
information regarding the structure of a
molecule irradiating substances with
electromagnetic radiation of specific
wavelengths and observing the
interaction IR spectroscopy is one such
technique so let's learn how this works
now
the IR in IR spectroscopy stands for
infrared so as one might guess this
technique involves irradiating a sample
with infrared radiation this is the
region of the electromagnetic spectrum
shown here the next section lower in
energy after visible light the reason we
do this is that infrared light is able
to induce specific types of motion in
the molecules in the sample we already
know that molecules are involved in
translational and rotational motion
translational motion allows molecules to
move around in space with respect to
each other and rotational motion allows
for all the sigma Bonds in the molecule
to be rotating all the time producing
the various conformations but chemical
bonds are also doing other things as
they can exhibit vibrational motion
bonds can stretch which means they can
expand and contract slightly this can be
done in a symmetric way with respect to
a central atom which looks like this or
in asymmetric fashion we call this
symmetric stretch and asymmetric stretch
we can also get bending where atoms will
twist a bit to expand and contract the
bond angles again this can be done in
symmetric or asymmetric fashion to
produce what we call symmetric Bend and
asymmetric Bend all of these vibrational
modes are induced by infrared light and
the specific frequency that will cause
these behaviors will depend on the
precise identity of the bond so carbon
carbon carbon oxygen carbon hydrogen
oxygen hydrogen these will all absorb
infrared light of differing wavelengths
so when light of varying wavelengths
passes through the sample the
wavelengths that don't make it to the
detector must have been absorbed by the
sample and this tells us what kinds of
functional groups are present in the
molecule the way we will be reporting
the wavelengths of ir radiation is using
their wave numbers wave number
represented by new with a bar over it is
the reciprocal of wavelength in
centimeters so it is expressed in
inverse centimeters
the useful region in an IR spectrum is
from 4000 to 400 inverse centimeters
meaning that 400 to 4000 Cycles fit in
one centimeter
the main thing to understand is that
with ir spectroscopy we are irradiating
a sample with infrared radiation seeing
which wavelengths pass through the
sample to the detector and which do not
and taking those that are not
transmitted as inducing some kind of
molecular motion which will be
characteristic of the missing
frequencies this tells us about the
functional groups present on a molecule
Professor Dave for check see you next
time
foreign